DAVID METCALF

Sacramento, CA 95816

Phone: 916-701-1849 | Email: davidmetcalfwork@gmail.com LinkedIn.com/in/david-codes | GitHub.com/gloriousLoaf | Portfolio: metcalf.dev

SUMMARY

I am a full stack web developer with a diverse background in management, service, hospitality and client satisfaction. My experience in customer-facing roles has sharpened my natural communication skills and made me a team player. The business management positions I have held have given me long term perspectives on goals and assessing outcomes. Using this unique perspective, I create web applications with a friendly, mobile user interface at their core. I completed a 24 week MERN full stack development certificate through UC Davis. In the workspace, I am proficient with either PC or Mac systems. I look forward to being part of a team that is driven to build the best possible modern web experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL Workbench, Robo 3T, VS Code, Git Bash, Postman

Tools: Mongoose, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, JSX, jQuery, Bootstrap

Concepts: Functional & OOP, ORM, MVC, algorithm design, agile and scrum methodology

PROJECTS

Snipit Social | github.com/gloriousLoaf/Snipit-Social | snipit-social.herokuapp.com

- A mobile social media web app with feed, followers, profiles and chat.
- I developed websocket chat rooms, React-Redux store and components, interactive navigation and third-party Oauth2 through a custom-built Context API.
- Tools: React, Redux, React-Bootstrap, Socket.io, Passport.js, MongoDB, Express, Node

Emoji Runner | github.com/gloriousLoaf/Emoji-Runner | emoji-runner.herokuapp.com

- A classic runner game with soundtrack and effects, secure login and score tracking.
- I engineered the in-game physics, progression, canvas, scoreboard and user interface.
- Tools: P5.js, MySQL, Express, Node, Handlebars & Sequelizer

Covid-19 Tracker | github.com/gloriousLoaf/Covid-19-Tracker | metcalf.dev/Covid-19-Tracker

- App that allows users to track global & local stats, testing info, and interactive map.
- I developed the API calls and logic for stats, news, local testing sites, and resources.
- Tools: ¡Query, ¡QueryUI, AJAX, Mapbox, IPAPI, Moment.js

EXPERIENCE

Remote Tutor, Full Stack Web Development 2U Inc. / Trilogy Education Coding Boot Camps

2020 – Present

Remote

Live one-on-one video tutoring sessions with boot camp students learning web development. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Providing educational and motivational support to students on a wide range of topics
- Coach and guide students through problem solving, debugging and online research
- Schedule, manage and host sessions through Calendly and Zoom, follow up via Slack

Front-end Developer MLtwist

2020 - Present

Remote / Sacramento, CA

Building presentational and smart components for MLtwist.com, a Machine Learning SaaS. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Using Next.js React framework and MaterialUI to create UX/UI for full stack site
- Connecting stateful components to backend by writing custom API

Tasting Room Manager Domaine de la Terre Rouge

2017 - 2019

Plymouth, CA

Oversaw all DTC operations of a 20,000 case production winery, including ecommerce *Key Accomplishments:*

- Grew online sales and website traffic by 10%, customer email database by 20%, and implemented regular data hygiene and auditing for maximized efficiency
- Mobilized service team to amplify in-store revenue and streamline payment processing
- Programmed retargeting tactics that deployed social media and web traffic analytics

Wine Broker Springboard Wine Company

2015 - 2017

Petaluma, CA

Represented family-owned Californian & European wineries throughout greater Sacramento *Key Accomplishments:*

- Expanded new accounts at a 4% increased rate, month over month
- Collaborated with small business owners by identifying new trends and providing the best products to meet their goals through achieving sustainable profitability

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Certificate: University of California, Davis

2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, the MERN stack, Git version control, accessibility and mobile responsiveness. Delivered 23 polished and functional web products, including three group projects. Repositories were reviewed for best practices, readability and maintainability.

Wine Business Management Certificate: California State University, Sonoma 2015

A year-long specialized program focused on mastering the management and direction of a profitable wine production business. This included vineyard management, winery planning and zoning, harvest, fermentation and ageing, bottling, warehousing, digital marketing, online sales, website management, CRM deployment and legal compliance per taxation and transportation.